Welcome to module 7, Real-World Verification Applications & VIP (SV/UVM). In this module you will apply the full methodology (planning, uvm env, coverage, regressions) to real-world style blocks and protocols (e.g., dma, uart/spi/i2c, custom ip) and design reusable verification ip (vip) ready for production..
Here is what you will learn in this module. Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to real-world style blocks and protocols (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C...
Before you start, make sure you have these prerequisites. See module README
Learning path. Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to real-world style blocks and protocols (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C, custom IP) and design reusable verification IP (VIP) ready...
Overview. Modules 1–6 built up your skills and infrastructure. Module 7 is about applying them to realistic verification challenges:
Next section: How to learn this module.
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Choose a real-world DUT or subsystem scope in module7/PROJECTS.md. Scaffold Module 7 workspace: ./scripts/module7.sh --scaffold Design reusable VIP structure in module7/VIP_DESIGN.md. Apply best practices from module7/BEST_PRACTICES.md to naming, docs, and API boundaries. Validate: ./scripts/module7.sh --check From...
Next section: Design architecture.
1. Real-world DUT / subsystem. Choose DMA-style block, bus/register IP, or protocol DUT (UART/SPI/I2C/AXI-lite style). Document block diagram, clocks/resets, and interface contracts in PROJECTS.md. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. VIP package architecture. Reusable VIP: agent, sequencer, driver, monitor, checker, coverage, config objects. VIP_DESIGN.md defines public API, sequences, and integration guide for adopters. Package boundaries: what integrators configure vs what VIP owns internally. Refer to the diagram on the right.
3. Production layout. Separate rtl/, tb/, tests/, docs/ with consistent naming for handoff to another team.
VIP design template. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Key files to study.
Open these in the repo. module7/PROJECTS.md — DUT scope, interfaces, and verification goals module7/VIP_DESIGN.md — VIP package architecture and public API module7/BEST_PRACTICES.md — production-quality verification and delivery standards module6/MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md — prior multi-agent patterns to reuse scripts/module7.sh — project and VIP design doc checks Trace while running...
Next section: Verification & testing methods.
1. End-to-end IP verification. Full lifecycle: requirements → env → tests → coverage → regressions → sign-off preview. Regression tiers and coverage goals match production expectations. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. VIP validation. Self-test environment for the VIP plus integrator tests on a reference DUT. Documentation-driven review: another engineer can adopt VIP from docs alone.
3. Quality bar. BEST_PRACTICES.md — coding standards, review checklist, maintenance and versioning. ./scripts/module7.sh --check validates project and VIP design documentation.
Project scope template. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
VIP best practices excerpt. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Syllabus topics.
1. End-to-End IP Verification. Applying planning + UVM + coverage + regression to realistic IP. Realistic test planning, coverage closure, and regression operation.
2. VIP Design and Reuse. Designing and documenting verification IP (VIP) for protocols or blocks.
3. Production Quality and Maintenance. Best practices for project structure, code quality, docs, and maintenance.
Next section: Command reference highlights.
Scaffold and validate Module 7. ./scripts/module7.sh --scaffold Full detail in docs/MODULE7.md command reference.
Review VIP and project templates. head -40 module7/templates/VIP_DESIGN.md Full detail in docs/MODULE7.md command reference.
Next section: Hands-on examples.
Module 7 self-check. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: VIP design template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Projects overview. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Best practices. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Reference VIP design. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Module validation. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Next section: Practice & assessment.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Design and implement a complete verification environment for a realistic DUT. Create and document reusable VIP that others could adopt. Operate regressions and coverage closure as you would in a real team. Maintain production-quality code, docs, and tests over the lifetime of a project. At least one substantial real-world style project is...
By now you should be able to explain the following. Best-practices checklist largely satisfied (module7/BEST_PRACTICES.md / module7/CHECKLIST.md). You can explain your project and design decisions as if presenting to a review board. From MODULE7 Learning Outcomes.
Assessment checklist. At least one substantial real-world style project is described and partially/fully implemented. VIP or environment design is documented in module7/VIP_DESIGN.md and module7/PROJECTS.md. Best-practices checklist largely satisfied (module7/BEST_PRACTICES.md / module7/CHECKLIST.md). You can explain your project and design decisions as if presenting to a review board.
In summary: Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to real-world style blocks and protocols (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C, custom IP) and design reusable verification IP (VIP) ready for production. Next up: Next module in course. Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to real-world style blocks and protocols (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C...