Regression Management & Advanced UVM Orchestration (SV/UVM) Module 5
Learning objectives Turn your test, coverage, and environment designs into a **robust regression system** that scales: advanced sequence orchestration (including virtual sequences), flake management, CI integration, performance tuning, and coverage-driven refinement.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Turn your test, coverage, and environment designs into a **robust regression system** that scales: advanced sequence orchestration (including virtual sequences), flake management, CI integration, performance tuning, and coverage-driven refinement.
Overview Modules 1–4 established **what to test**, **how to measure**, and **how to build a solid UVM environment**.   In Module 5, you focus on **running that environment at scale**:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 5: DUT structure and key interfaces (see common_dut/rtl/).
Verification environment architecture Module 5: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE5 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 5: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE5 Verification & Testing Methods.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE5 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Hands-on: module5/examples/regression_ops/
Hands-on: module5/examples/debug_flake/
Hands-on: module5/examples/advanced_uvm/
Hands-on: module5/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module5/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
Exercises Runtime Tuning Coverage-Driven Job Resilience Drill
Assessment checklist Concrete regression jobs and commands captured in `module5/REGRESSION_OPS.md`. Virtual sequence and advanced UVM usage planned in `module5/ADVANCED_UVM_PLAN.md`. Flake and debug strategy documented in `module5/DEBUG_FLAKE_PLAN.md`. Regression flows demonstrably support coverage and sign-off goals.
Summary & next steps Turn your test, coverage, and environment designs into a **robust regression system** that scales: advanced sequence orchestration (including virtual sequences), flake management, CI integration, performance tuning, and coverage-driven refinement. Complete module5/CHECKLIST.md Run ./scripts/module5.sh --check Next: Next module in course