UVM Environment & Checker Maturity (SV/UVM) Module 4
Learning objectives Design and mature your **UVM environment** (env, agents, drivers, monitors, sequencers) and **checking strategy** (scoreboards, reference models, protocol/functional assertions) so that your test and coverage plans from earlier modules can be executed reliably at scale.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Design and mature your **UVM environment** (env, agents, drivers, monitors, sequencers) and **checking strategy** (scoreboards, reference models, protocol/functional assertions) so that your test and coverage plans from earlier modules can be executed reliably at scale.
Overview Modules 1–3 focused on planning (scope, tests, regressions) and measurement (coverage).   In Module 4, you focus on the **quality and structure of the verification environment itself**:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 4: DUT structure and key interfaces (see common_dut/rtl/).
Verification environment architecture Module 4: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE4 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 4: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE4 Verification & Testing Methods.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE4 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Hands-on: module4/examples/env_design/
Hands-on: module4/examples/checker_plan/
Hands-on: module4/examples/module_tb/
Hands-on: module4/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module4/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
Assessment checklist UVM env/agent architecture documented in `module4/ENV_DESIGN.md`. Transaction and sequence designs documented and aligned with `module2/TEST_PLAN.md`. Scoreboards and reference models specified in `module4/CHECKER_PLAN.md`. Key protocol/functional assertions listed and placed. At least one env/checker review (self or peer) completed; action items captured.
Summary & next steps Design and mature your **UVM environment** (env, agents, drivers, monitors, sequencers) and **checking strategy** (scoreboards, reference models, protocol/functional assertions) so that your test and coverage plans from earlier modules can be executed reliably at scale. Complete module4/CHECKLIST.md Run ./scripts/module4.sh --check Next: Next module in course