Capstone – End‑to‑End Verification & VIP Delivery (SV/UVM) Module 8
Learning objectives Plan and execute a **single, substantial capstone project** that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through UVM environment, coverage, regressions, and delivery of a reusable **verification solution or VIP**.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Plan and execute a **single, substantial capstone project** that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through UVM environment, coverage, regressions, and delivery of a reusable **verification solution or VIP**.
Overview Module 8 is not another theory module; it is a **major project** that ties everything together:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 8: DUT structure and key interfaces (see common_dut/rtl/).
Verification environment architecture Module 8: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE8 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 8: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE8 Verification & Testing Methods.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Hands-on: module8/examples/capstone/
Hands-on: module8/examples/checklist/
Hands-on: module8/examples/fill_guides/
Hands-on: module8/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module8/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
Assessment checklist A clearly defined capstone project documented in `capstone_project.md`. Evidence that Modules 1–7 have been applied (plans, env, tests, coverage, regressions). A “deliverable” verification solution or VIP (code + docs) that could be handed to another team. A short written or presented retrospective on what worked, what didn’t, and what you’d improve next.
Summary & next steps Plan and execute a **single, substantial capstone project** that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through UVM environment, coverage, regressions, and delivery of a reusable **verification solution or VIP**. Complete module8/CHECKLIST.md Run ./scripts/module8.sh --check Next: Next module in course