Complex Multi-Agent & Protocol Testbenches (SV/UVM) Module 6
Learning objectives Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to **complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches** (e.g., AXI-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking, and maintainability.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to **complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches** (e.g., AXI-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking, and maintainability.
Overview By Module 6, you have:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 6: DUT structure and key interfaces (see common_dut/rtl/).
Verification environment architecture Module 6: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE6 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 6: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE6 Verification & Testing Methods.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE6 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Hands-on: module6/examples/protocol_plan/
Hands-on: module6/examples/multi_agent/
Hands-on: module6/examples/integration/
Hands-on: module6/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module6/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
Assessment checklist Multi-agent/multi-channel environment design documented in `module6/MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md`. Protocol verification strategy documented in `module6/PROTOCOL_VERIFICATION_PLAN.md`. Integration patterns and system-level scenarios documented in `module6/INTEGRATION_PLAN.md`. Complex bench design reviewed; action items captured in the docs.
Summary & next steps Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to **complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches** (e.g., AXI-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking, and maintainability. Complete module6/CHECKLIST.md Run ./scripts/module6.sh --check Next: Next module in course