Welcome to module 6, Complex Multi-Agent & Protocol Testbenches (SV/UVM). In this module you will apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches (e.g., axi-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking, and maintainability..
Here is what you will learn in this module. Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches (e.g., AXI-like...
Before you start, make sure you have these prerequisites. See module README
Learning path. Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches (e.g., AXI-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking...
Overview. By Module 6, you have:
Next section: How to learn this module.
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Re-read module4/ENV_DESIGN.md and module5/REGRESSION_OPS.md. Scaffold Module 6 workspace: ./scripts/module6.sh --scaffold Complete MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md, PROTOCOL_VERIFICATION_PLAN.md, and INTEGRATION_PLAN.md. Add or refine multi-agent and protocol checker components in common_dut/tb/. Validate: ./scripts/module6.sh...
Next section: Design architecture.
1. Multi-agent / multi-channel TB. Multiple agents (per interface or channel) coordinated by env and virtual sequences. Layered architecture: block agents → fabric/scoreboard → subsystem scenarios (MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md). Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Protocol verification layer. Dedicated protocol checker (SVA or monitor-based) separate from scoreboard data checks. PROTOCOL_VERIFICATION_PLAN.md lists rules, coverage, and integration with agents. Refer to the diagram on the right.
3. System integration view. INTEGRATION_PLAN.md describes how block-level env connects to subsystem tests. Reuse agents/VIP across DUT variants via configuration and factory overrides.
Monitor observes transactions. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Multi-agent architecture template. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Key files to study.
Open these in the repo. module6/MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md — multi-channel env and virtual sequence coordination module6/PROTOCOL_VERIFICATION_PLAN.md — protocol rules, checkers, and coverage module6/INTEGRATION_PLAN.md — block-to-subsystem integration strategy module4/tb/stream_pkg.sv — monitor and agent patterns to extend scripts/module6.sh — multi-agent and protocol doc checks Trace while...
Next section: Verification & testing methods.
1. Protocol rule testing. Each protocol rule maps to checker fires, coverpoints, and at least one directed or random test. Illegal sequences and corner timing documented with expected checker behavior. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Multi-agent scenario testing. Virtual sequences stress cross-agent ordering, arbitration, and backpressure. System scoreboard validates end-to-end data and sideband signals.
3. Maintainability reviews. Architecture review before adding agents — avoid duplicate monitors and conflicting checkers. ./scripts/module6.sh --check validates multi-agent and protocol planning artifacts.
Protocol verification plan excerpt. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Syllabus topics.
1. Multi-Agent Environment Design. Multi-agent and multi-channel environment design. Layered and reusable testbench architecture patterns.
2. Protocol Agents and Checkers. Protocol agent and protocol checker design.
3. Scoreboards and Integration. Integration of complex scoreboards and time-based matching.
4. Debug and Analysis. Debugging and analyzing complex, protocol-heavy simulations.
Next section: Command reference highlights.
Scaffold and validate Module 6. ./scripts/module6.sh --scaffold Full detail in docs/MODULE6.md command reference.
Review multi-agent architecture template. head -40 module6/templates/MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md Full detail in docs/MODULE6.md command reference.
Next section: Hands-on examples.
Module 6 self-check. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Exercise scaffold. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Demo: Protocol verification plan. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Multi-agent architecture. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Integration plan. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Reference protocol plan. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Module validation. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Next section: Practice & assessment.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Design and document multi-agent UVM environments for protocol-based DUTs. Implement and integrate protocol agents and protocol checkers. Apply layered architecture patterns to keep complex benches maintainable. Analyze and debug multi-channel, protocol-level behavior in simulations. Multi-agent/multi-channel environment design documented in...
By now you should be able to explain the following. Integration patterns and system-level scenarios documented in module6/INTEGRATION_PLAN.md. Complex bench design reviewed; action items captured in the docs. From MODULE6 Learning Outcomes.
Assessment checklist. Multi-agent/multi-channel environment design documented in module6/MULTI_AGENT_ARCHITECTURE.md. Protocol verification strategy documented in module6/PROTOCOL_VERIFICATION_PLAN.md. Integration patterns and system-level scenarios documented in module6/INTEGRATION_PLAN.md. Complex bench design reviewed; action items captured in the docs.
In summary: Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches (e.g., AXI-like, multi-channel interfaces), focusing on architecture, protocol checking, and maintainability. Next up: Next module in course. Apply your planning, environment, and regression skills to complex multi-agent, protocol-heavy testbenches (e.g., AXI-like... Complete...