Welcome to module 8, Capstone – End‑to‑End Verification & VIP Delivery (SV/UVM). In this module you will plan and execute a single, substantial capstone project that exercises the full verification lifecycle (modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through uvm environment, coverage, regressions, and delivery of a reusable verification solution or vip..
Here is what you will learn in this module. Plan and execute a single, substantial capstone project that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements...
Before you start, make sure you have these prerequisites. See module README
Learning path. Plan and execute a single, substantial capstone project that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through UVM environment, coverage, regressions...
Overview. Module 8 is not another theory module; it is a major project that ties everything together:
Next section: How to learn this module.
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Select capstone DUT and scope in module8/CAPSTONE_PROJECT.md. Scaffold Module 8 workspace: ./scripts/module8.sh --scaffold Assemble artifacts from Modules 1–7: plans, env, coverage, regression ops, VIP (if applicable). Run full regression tiers and document sign-off status in the capstone checklist. Validate deliverable...
Next section: Design architecture.
1. Capstone system architecture. CAPSTONE_PROJECT.md defines DUT hierarchy, interfaces, clocks, and verification scope. Apply Modules 1–7 artifacts: plans, env, VIP (if applicable), coverage, regression ops. Deliverable layout: RTL, UVM env, tests, scripts, and user-facing documentation. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. End-to-end verification package. Single coherent verification solution or VIP another team can integrate. Traceability matrix from requirements through tests, coverage, and sign-off criteria. Refer to the diagram on the right.
3. Capstone delivery and handoff workflow. Plan: consolidate Modules 1–2 plans into capstone scope and test/regression strategy. Build: mature env, checkers, coverage, and VIP (Module 4–7 artifacts) under rtl/ and tb/. Execute: run sanity → core → stress tiers; merge coverage; triage failures with saved seeds. Sign off: meet exit criteria in CAPSTONE_PROJECT.md; complete CHECKLIST.md. Deliver...
Capstone project plan template. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Key files to study.
Open these in the repo. module8/CAPSTONE_PROJECT.md — end-to-end project definition and deliverables module8/CHECKLIST.md — capstone sign-off and delivery checklist docs/FILL_GUIDES.md — guidance for completing planning artifacts Prior module workspaces (module1/ … module7/) — reusable verification assets scripts/module8.sh — capstone documentation and checklist validation Trace while running...
Next section: Verification & testing methods.
1. Full-lifecycle testing. Execute planned regression tiers with coverage merge and documented closure status. Include negative, stress, and protocol/rule tests appropriate to your capstone DUT. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Sign-off and delivery testing. Define explicit exit criteria (coverage %, bug bar, stability window). Retrospective: what worked, gaps, and improvements for a real project review.
3. Validation. ./scripts/module8.sh --check validates capstone documentation and checklist completion. Optional demo or walkthrough recorded as part of the deliverable.
Capstone checklist excerpt. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Capstone validation script. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Command reference highlights.
Scaffold and validate capstone. ./scripts/module8.sh --scaffold Full detail in docs/MODULE8.md command reference.
Review capstone templates. head -45 module8/templates/CAPSTONE_PROJECT.md Full detail in docs/MODULE8.md command reference.
Next section: Hands-on examples.
Module 8 self-check. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Capstone project template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Capstone checklist. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Fill guides. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Reference capstone. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Module validation. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Next section: Practice & assessment.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Drive an end‑to‑end verification effort from requirements → plan → env → tests → coverage → regressions → sign‑off. Deliver a coherent, documented verification package or VIP that others can understand and use. Reflect on trade‑offs and improvements as if you were preparing for a real project review. A clearly defined capstone project...
By now you should be able to explain the following. A short written or presented retrospective on what worked, what didn’t, and what you’d improve next. From MODULE8 Learning Outcomes.
Assessment checklist. A clearly defined capstone project documented in capstone_project.md. Evidence that Modules 1–7 have been applied (plans, env, tests, coverage, regressions). A “deliverable” verification solution or VIP (code + docs) that could be handed to another team. A short written or presented retrospective on what worked, what didn’t, and what you’d improve next.
In summary: Plan and execute a single, substantial capstone project that exercises the full verification lifecycle (Modules 1–7), from requirements and planning through UVM environment, coverage, regressions, and delivery of a reusable verification solution or VIP. Next up: Next module in course. Plan and execute a single, substantial capstone project that exercises the full verification...