Welcome to module 1, Verification Planning & Management Foundations (SV/UVM). In this module you will learn how to turn a dut specification into a concrete verification plan, with clear strategy, coverage intent, and regression approach, using verilog duts and systemverilog/uvm testbenches..
Here is what you will learn in this module. Learn how to turn a DUT specification into a concrete verification plan, with clear strategy, coverage intent, and regression approach...
Before you start, make sure you have these prerequisites. See module README
Learning path. Learn how to turn a DUT specification into a concrete verification plan, with clear strategy, coverage intent, and regression approach, using Verilog DUTs and SystemVerilog/UVM testbenches.
Overview. This module establishes the foundation for verification planning and management. Instead of starting from coding UVM components, you...
Next section: How to learn this module.
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Read this module doc and module1/README.md for objectives and workspace layout. Scaffold planning files if needed: ./scripts/module1.sh --scaffold Edit module1/VERIFICATION_PLAN.md and module1/REQUIREMENTS_MATRIX.md from templates. Inspect shared DUT RTL at common_dut/rtl/stream_fifo.sv and the TB skeleton under...
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Complete module1/CHECKLIST.md before starting Module 2. From docs/MODULE1.md — read guides before running demos.
Next section: Design architecture.
1. Stream FIFO DUT (shared course RTL). Course DUT: common_dut/rtl/stream_fifo.sv — parameterizable DEPTH and DATA_WIDTH. Source interface: s_valid, s_ready, s_data (push when both valid and ready). Sink interface: m_valid, m_ready, m_data (pop on handshake). Internal storage: circular buffer (mem, wr_ptr, rd_ptr, count). Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Planning-level verification view (Module 1). No full UVM implementation required yet — document intended env boundaries in VERIFICATION_PLAN.md. REQUIREMENTS_MATRIX.md traces features → future tests and coverage bins. common_dut/tb/ holds skeleton stubs so architecture decisions are concrete, not abstract. Refer to the diagram on the right.
3. Repository layout and planning workflow. Inputs: DUT spec, course README, Module 1 templates and optional solutions. Workspace: edit module1/*.md planning documents directly in the repository. Shared RTL/TB: common_dut/ holds the physical DUT and skeleton env reused in later modules. Validation loop: edit plan → run ./scripts/module1.sh --check → fix TODOs → checklist sign-off. Outputs...
DUT — stream_fifo ports. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
UVM env skeleton. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Key files to study.
Open these in the repo (1/2). module1/VERIFICATION_PLAN.md — verification strategy, scope, and test intents module1/REQUIREMENTS_MATRIX.md — requirements-to-test traceability module1/templates/ — empty templates for a fresh start module1/.solutions/ — reference solutions (optional comparison) common_dut/rtl/stream_fifo.sv — shared course DUT (stream FIFO) Trace while running...
Open these in the repo (2/2). scripts/module1.sh — validation and scaffold orchestrator Trace while running module1/EXAMPLES.md labs.
Next section: Verification & testing methods.
1. Planning-first methodology. Start from spec → scope → strategy before writing large amounts of testbench code. Use risk-based prioritization to decide what to verify first in later modules. Separate verification objectives (quality/risk) from implementation details. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Test intent and validation (Module 1). Capture test intents (names, goals, tiers) in the verification plan — not full UVM tests yet. Directed vs constrained-random choices are documented with rationale for the FIFO DUT. Self-check: ./scripts/module1.sh --check validates planning artifacts; simulation is optional.
3. Early closure thinking. Sketch functional coverage intent and regression tiers (sanity / nightly / full) for later modules. Define sign-off preview criteria (coverage goals, bug bars) in the plan from day one.
Module 1 — validation commands. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Syllabus topics.
1. Verification Mindset and Goals (1/2). Design vs Verification What verification is responsible for (and what it is not). “Bug-finding” vs “quality and risk management”. Verification Objectives Proving conformance to spec (as far as practical).
1. Verification Mindset and Goals (2/2). Balancing schedule, quality, and resources. UVM/SV Context Why constrained-random and coverage-driven verification (CDV) matter. Where SV/UVM and Verilog DUTs fit in the overall flow.
2. From Specification to Verification Scope (1/2). Requirements Intake Extracting verifiable requirements from a product/design spec. Identifying interfaces, modes, configurations, and corner cases. Capturing assumptions and dependencies (e.g., upstream/downstream blocks, firmware behavior). In-Scope vs Out-of-Scope
2. From Specification to Verification Scope (2/2). Handling legacy behavior, debug features, and low-priority modes. Risk-Based Prioritization High-risk vs low-risk features. Safety/criticality, complexity, novelty, and usage frequency.
3. Verification Strategy (SV/UVM Focus) (1/2). Strategy Dimensions Directed vs constrained-random vs scenario-based testing. Use of reference models, assertions, and protocol checkers. Layered testbench and reuse (block/IP → subsystem → SoC). UVM Testbench Architecture Concepts
3. Verification Strategy (SV/UVM Focus) (2/2). Mapping features and scenarios to sequences and configuration knobs. Choosing Strategies for the DUT For a FIFO: corner-case heavy, error injection, stress tests. For a bus/reg block: protocol correctness, access patterns, error responses. For a UART: timing, framing/parity errors, flow control.
3. Verification flow. Stimulus, observation, and check strategy for this module.
4. Test Planning and Test Catalogue Basics (1/2). Test Intent vs Test Implementation Writing test descriptions at the intent level (what to prove). Mapping intents to one or more concrete UVM tests/sequences. Test Types and Tiers Smoke/sanity vs feature tests vs stress/error-injection.
4. Test Planning and Test Catalogue Basics (2/2). Early Test Catalogue Building a first-pass list of 10–20 key tests/intents from the spec. Tagging each with requirements, priority, and expected coverage impact.
5. Coverage Planning Primer (1/2). Why Coverage is Central to Planning Functional vs code coverage and their roles. “Coverage as a question”: what do you need to know to sleep at night? Sketching Coverage Models Listing features, modes, and scenarios that deserve covergroups.
5. Coverage Planning Primer (2/2). Defining Initial Coverage Goals Setting measurable but realistic targets. Separating “must cover” from “nice to have”.
6. Intro to Regression and Sign-off Thinking. Regression at a High Level Why we need repeatable, automated regressions. Basic tiers (sanity / nightly / full). Sign-off Preview Types of sign-off criteria: coverage, bug bars, waivers, stability.
Next section: Command reference highlights.
Scaffold planning workspace. ./scripts/module1.sh --scaffold Full detail in docs/MODULE1.md command reference.
Validate Module 1 artifacts. ./scripts/module1.sh --check Full detail in docs/MODULE1.md command reference.
Inspect templates and shared DUT. head -30 module1/templates/VERIFICATION_PLAN.md Full detail in docs/MODULE1.md command reference.
Next section: Hands-on examples.
Module 1 self-check. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Exercise scaffold. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Demo: Verification plan template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Requirements matrix template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Reference solution. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Shared DUT RTL. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Module validation. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Next section: Practice & assessment.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Explain the role of verification and its relationship to design. Turn a DUT specification into a verification scope with clear assumptions and boundaries. Draft a verification strategy for a simple Verilog DUT and SV/UVM environment. Create an initial test catalogue (test intents) linked to requirements. Sketch a coverage plan (what to...
By now you should be able to explain the following. Given a short DUT spec (e.g., FIFO or UART), list: Functional requirements (what the DUT must do). Non-functional/quality requirements (throughput, latency constraints, etc.). Assumptions and environment constraints. Classify each requirement as must-have, nice-to-have, or future. From MODULE1 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Choose your DUT (FIFO / UART / AXI-lite block / your own). In module1/VERIFICATION_PLAN.md, add sections for: Objectives and success criteria. High-level SV/UVM environment concept (env, agents, scoreboard, reference model). Use of directed, random, and scenario-based tests. From MODULE1 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Keep the strategy to 1–2 pages maximum. Create a table with columns: Test ID Test name Intent / description From MODULE1 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Priority (H/M/L) Type (smoke/feature/stress/error) Populate at least 10 test intents for your DUT. From your requirement list and test catalogue, identify: Signals/fields that deserve coverpoints (e.g., addresses, opcodes, status flags, error types). From MODULE1 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Write a brief description (no code required yet) of: Where each covergroup would live in the UVM testbench (monitor, scoreboard, etc.). What hitting those bins would tell you about verification completeness. From MODULE1 Learning Outcomes.
Exercises. Scope and Risk Matrix Assumption Log UVM Architecture Sketch
Assessment checklist. Can explain verification’s role and goals in the SV/UVM context. Has produced a written verification scope (in-scope, out-of-scope, assumptions). Has a concise verification strategy document for the chosen DUT. Has an initial test catalogue with traceability to requirements. Has a high-level coverage plan (what to cover and why).
In summary: Learn how to turn a DUT specification into a concrete verification plan, with clear strategy, coverage intent, and regression approach, using Verilog DUTs and SystemVerilog/UVM testbenches. Next up: Test Planning & Strategy in Depth. Learn how to turn a DUT specification into a concrete verification plan, with clear strategy, coverage intent, and regression approach... Complete...