Real-World Verification Applications & VIP (SV/UVM) Module 7
Learning objectives Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to **real-world style blocks and protocols** (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C, custom IP) and design **reusable verification IP (VIP)** ready for production.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to **real-world style blocks and protocols** (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C, custom IP) and design **reusable verification IP (VIP)** ready for production.
Overview Modules 1–6 built up your **skills and infrastructure**.   Module 7 is about **applying** them to realistic verification challenges:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 7: DUT structure and key interfaces (see common_dut/rtl/).
Verification environment architecture Module 7: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE7 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 7: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE7 Verification & Testing Methods.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE7 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Hands-on: module7/examples/vip_design/
Hands-on: module7/examples/projects/
Hands-on: module7/examples/best_practices/
Hands-on: module7/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module7/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
Assessment checklist At least one substantial real-world style project is described and partially/fully implemented. VIP or environment design is documented in `module7/VIP_DESIGN.md` and `module7/PROJECTS.md`. Best-practices checklist largely satisfied (`module7/BEST_PRACTICES.md` / `module7/CHECKLIST.md`). You can explain your project and design decisions as if presenting to a review board.
Summary & next steps Apply the full methodology (planning, UVM env, coverage, regressions) to **real-world style blocks and protocols** (e.g., DMA, UART/SPI/I2C, custom IP) and design **reusable verification IP (VIP)** ready for production. Complete module7/CHECKLIST.md Run ./scripts/module7.sh --check Next: Next module in course