Test Planning & Strategy in Depth (SV/UVM) Module 2
Learning objectives Turn your initial verification plan into a detailed, reviewable **test strategy**, with a structured test catalogue, negative/stress planning, and an initial regression tiering concept for your Verilog DUT and SV/UVM environment.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Turn your initial verification plan into a detailed, reviewable **test strategy**, with a structured test catalogue, negative/stress planning, and an initial regression tiering concept for your Verilog DUT and SV/UVM environment.
Overview Module 1 gave you a high-level verification plan, scope, and early test catalogue.   In this module, you will:
Design architecture
RTL / block architecture Module 2: DUT / block hierarchy (see module2/examples/).
Verification environment architecture Module 2: UVM layers, agents, and checkers for this phase.
From MODULE2 Design Architecture.
Verification & testing methods
Testing and closure flow Module 2: how tests, checks, and metrics close verification goals.
From MODULE2 Verification & Testing Methods.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE2 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Hands-on: module2/examples/test_plan/
Hands-on: module2/examples/regression_plan/
Hands-on: module2/examples/coverage_plan/
Hands-on: module2/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module2/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
From MODULE2 Learning Outcomes.
Exercises Runtime Budgeting Flake-Resistance Design Traceability Check
Assessment checklist Has a written test taxonomy and tier definition. Test catalogue expanded and de-duplicated with clear metadata. Negative, stress, and corner-case tests are explicitly planned. Seed and randomness policy is documented. A draft regression plan exists with test-to-tier mapping. Requirements and coverage implications are reflected in the updated plan/matrix.
Summary & next steps Turn your initial verification plan into a detailed, reviewable **test strategy**, with a structured test catalogue, negative/stress planning, and an initial regression tiering concept for your Verilog DUT and SV/UVM environment. Complete module2/CHECKLIST.md Review module2/EXAMPLES.md and run each lab Next: Coverage Planning & Analysis in Practice