Welcome to module 3, Coverage Planning & Analysis in Practice (SV/UVM). In this module you will design and implement a practical coverage model (functional + code), connect it to your uvm environment and test plan, and perform first real coverage analysis and gap-closing cycles on your verilog dut..
Here is what you will learn in this module. Design and implement a practical coverage model (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first...
Before you start, make sure you have these prerequisites. See module README
Learning path. Design and implement a practical coverage model (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first real coverage analysis and gap-closing cycles on your...
Overview. Modules 1–2 focused on what to test and how to structure tests and regressions. Module 3 turns coverage from a conceptual plan into a...
Next section: How to learn this module.
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Re-open module2/TEST_PLAN.md and module2/COVERAGE_PLAN.md. Scaffold Module 3 workspace: ./scripts/module3.sh --scaffold Design covergroups in module3/COVERAGE_DESIGN.md and plan runs in COVERAGE_RUN.md. Implement or review common_dut/tb/stream_fifo_coverage.sv covergroup definitions. Run a small CORE-tier regression and...
Follow this learning path. Read the guides before running the labs. Validate: ./scripts/module3.sh --check From docs/MODULE3.md — read guides before running demos.
Next section: Design architecture.
1. Coverage in the UVM environment. Functional coverage lives in common_dut/tb/stream_fifo_coverage.sv (covergroups, crosses). Monitors/agents sample transactions that feed coverpoints (fill level, handshake patterns, errors). COVERAGE_DESIGN.md is the authoritative map from requirements → coverpoints → tests. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Code coverage integration. Simulator line/branch/FSM coverage configured in your run scripts (documented in COVERAGE_RUN.md). Separate functional vs code coverage roles: intent vs implementation exercised. Refer to the diagram on the right.
3. Coverage run and merge pipeline. Run: select CORE-tier tests → enable functional + code coverage in simulator → save per-test databases. Merge: combine run databases into a session or regression snapshot for analysis. Analyze: compare merged coverage against goals in COVERAGE_PLAN.md; record gaps in COVERAGE_RUN.md. Close: add targeted tests or refine coverpoints; re-run until must-cover...
Coverage model — covergroups. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Key files to study.
Open these in the repo. module3/COVERAGE_DESIGN.md — coverpoints, crosses, and requirement mapping module3/COVERAGE_RUN.md — run logs, merge steps, and gap analysis notes common_dut/tb/stream_fifo_coverage.sv — functional coverage implementation module2/COVERAGE_PLAN.md — coverage goals and tier linkage scripts/module3.sh — coverage design and TB presence checks Trace while running...
Next section: Verification & testing methods.
1. Coverage-driven verification (CDV). Run a CORE-tier regression subset, merge coverage, and compare against goals in COVERAGE_PLAN.md. Use gap analysis to add targeted tests or relax/remove low-value bins — not blind random runs. Refer to the diagram on the right.
2. Closure loop. Requirements → tests → coverpoints → measured bins → updated plan/tests. ./scripts/module3.sh --check expects covergroup references and coverage design docs.
3. Reporting discipline. Log each run in COVERAGE_RUN.md with tool, seed, tier, and top uncovered items.
sample() integration point. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Module 3 — coverage checks. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Next section: Syllabus topics.
1. From Coverage Plan to Concrete Model. Refinement of Coverage Goals Translating high-level goals into specific covergroups and bins. Deciding which metrics are *must-hit* vs *nice-to-have*. Coverage Model Structure Organizing covergroups by feature, interface, or component.
2. Functional Coverage Implementation (SV/UVM) (1/2). Covergroup Basics covergroup declaration, sampling events (@), and options. Coverpoints: bins, ranges, wildcards, ignore/illegal bins. Cross coverage: when and how to cross (and when not to). Sampling Strategy
2. Functional Coverage Implementation (SV/UVM) (2/2). Avoiding oversampling/undersampling. Integration with UVM Components Embedding covergroups in monitors/scoreboards. Using analysis ports/exports for coverage sampling.
3. Code Coverage Setup and Interpretation (1/2). Enabling Code Coverage Turning on statement/branch/toggle coverage in your simulator. Handling compile-time options and run-time switches. Interpreting Results Reading coverage reports and understanding common metrics.
3. Code Coverage Setup and Interpretation (2/2). Managing Exclusions Identifying truly unreachable code. Documenting exclusions and waivers with rationale.
4. Running Coverage-Enabled Regressions (1/2). Pilot Regressions Start with a modest CORE-tier run (not full regression). Ensure coverage data collection is working end-to-end. Merging Coverage Combining coverage from multiple tests/regressions.
4. Running Coverage-Enabled Regressions (2/2). Automating Coverage Collection Hooks in your regression/CI scripts to generate coverage databases/reports.
5. Coverage Analysis and Gap Closure (1/3). Gap Identification Finding unhit or low-hit coverpoints and crosses. Detecting missing or ineffective coverage (bins that never can be hit). Root-Cause Analysis Is the gap due to:
5. Coverage Analysis and Gap Closure (2/3). Overly tight constraints? Incomplete coverage model? Truly unreachable or out-of-scope functionality? Closure Actions Adding or modifying tests (directed or constrained-random).
5. Coverage Analysis and Gap Closure (3/3). Refining or pruning coverage points. Documenting waivers where appropriate.
6. Connecting Coverage to Requirements and Sign-off (1/2). Traceability Ensuring high-priority requirements are covered by both tests and coverage. Updating REQUIREMENTS_MATRIX.md with coverage IDs and status. Interpreting Coverage for Sign-off Understanding when “100% coverage” is meaningful (and when it isn’t).
6. Connecting Coverage to Requirements and Sign-off (2/2). Preparing for Later Modules How coverage insights will influence later regression and sign-off modules.
Next section: Command reference highlights.
Scaffold and validate Module 3. ./scripts/module3.sh --scaffold Full detail in docs/MODULE3.md command reference.
Inspect coverage model in TB. head -60 common_dut/tb/stream_fifo_coverage.sv Full detail in docs/MODULE3.md command reference.
Next section: Hands-on examples.
Module 3 self-check. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Exercise scaffold. Review the code on screen and match it to files in the repository.
Demo: Coverage design template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Coverage run log template. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: TB coverage skeleton. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Reference coverage design. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Demo: Module validation. Watch the terminal output and confirm you see the expected pass message.
Next section: Practice & assessment.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Design and implement a concrete functional coverage model for your DUT. Enable and collect code coverage from your simulator. Run coverage-enabled regressions and interpret coverage reports. Perform a structured coverage gap analysis and plan closure actions. Tie coverage results back to requirements and sign-off criteria. From MODULE3...
By now you should be able to explain the following. For each, implement: At least one covergroup with meaningful coverpoints. At least one useful cross (if warranted). Integrate sampling into your UVM monitor/scoreboard. Verify that bins are being hit in basic tests (e.g., SANITY/CORE tests). From MODULE3 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Run a small set of tests (e.g., SANITY or a subset of CORE). Generate and inspect the coverage report. Identify: Any obvious coverage gaps in well-understood code. Any code that appears to be unreachable or out-of-scope. From MODULE3 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Date, DUT version, test set/tier, seed policy, simulator version. Key coverage metrics (summary) and major observations. List at least 5 concrete coverage gaps and your initial hypotheses. For at least 3 significant gaps: Decide whether to: add tests, tune constraints, refine coverage, or waive. From MODULE3 Learning Outcomes.
By now you should be able to explain the following. Update: module2/TEST_PLAN.md (new/updated tests). module2/COVERAGE_PLAN.md / module3/COVERAGE_DESIGN.md. module1/REQUIREMENTS_MATRIX.md (coverage mappings, waivers). From MODULE3 Learning Outcomes.
Exercises. Over-Coverage vs Under-Coverage Coverage vs Bug History (if available) Tooling Experiment
Assessment checklist. Functional coverage model implemented for key features/interfaces. Code coverage successfully enabled and reports generated. At least one coverage run documented in COVERAGE_RUN.md. Coverage gaps identified and categorized (test/constraint/model/waiver). Closure actions planned and reflected in test/coverage/requirements docs.
In summary: Design and implement a practical coverage model (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first real coverage analysis and gap-closing cycles on your Verilog DUT. Next up: UVM Environment and Checker Maturity. Design and implement a practical coverage model (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform...