Coverage Planning & Analysis in Practice (SV/UVM) Module 3
Learning objectives Design and implement a practical **coverage model** (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first real **coverage analysis and gap-closing** cycles on your Verilog DUT.
Prerequisites See module README
Learning path Design and implement a practical **coverage model** (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first real **coverage analysis and gap-closing** cycles on your Verilog DUT.
Overview Modules 1–2 focused on **what to test** and **how to structure tests and regressions**.   Module 3 turns coverage from a conceptual plan into a **measured, actionable signal**:
Design architecture
From MODULE3 Design Architecture.
Coverage model — covergroups The following command is shown on screen.
Verification & testing methods
From MODULE3 Verification & Testing Methods.
sample() integration point The following command is shown on screen.
Syllabus topics
From MODULE3 Topics Covered.
Hands-on examples
Run from course repository root.
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Hands-on: module3/examples/coverage_design/
Hands-on: module3/examples/coverage_run/
Hands-on: module3/examples/tb_coverage/
Hands-on: module3/examples/solutions/
Hands-on: module3/examples/validate/
Practice & assessment
From MODULE3 Learning Outcomes.
Exercises Over-Coverage vs Under-Coverage Coverage vs Bug History (if available) Tooling Experiment
Assessment checklist Functional coverage model implemented for key features/interfaces. Code coverage successfully enabled and reports generated. At least one coverage run documented in `COVERAGE_RUN.md`. Coverage gaps identified and categorized (test/constraint/model/waiver). Closure actions planned and reflected in test/coverage/requirements docs.
Summary & next steps Design and implement a practical **coverage model** (functional + code), connect it to your UVM environment and test plan, and perform first real **coverage analysis and gap-closing** cycles on your Verilog DUT. Complete module3/CHECKLIST.md Review module3/EXAMPLES.md and run each lab Next: UVM Environment and Checker Maturity